Partial Inventory of the Oleg Antonovich Krasovskii papers, 1934-2000.
Hoover Institution Archives
Oleg Antonovich Krasovskii papers
1934-2000
2013C19
Hoover Institution Archives
101 manuscript boxes, 11 oversize boxes, 3 cardfile boxes, 5 audiotapes (48 linear feet)
Writings, correspondence, printed matter, photographs, and sound recordings, relating to Russian nationalism, Russian émigré affairs, and Radio Liberty broadcasts to the Soviet Union. Includes manuscripts submitted to Veche and editorial correspondence of the journal.
Krasovskii, Oleg Antonovich, 1919-1993.
Access
The collection is open for research. The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. Use copies of some sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material in this collection are available for immediate access. To listen to other sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2013.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical note
Russian émigré journalist; Radio Liberty broadcast writer; editor and publisher, Veche (Munich, Germany).
Scope and Contents note
Writings, correspondence, printed matter, photographs, and sound recordings, relating to Russian nationalism, Russian émigré affairs, and Radio Liberty broadcasts to the Soviet Union. Includes manuscripts submitted to Veche and editorial correspondence of the journal.
Radio Liberty (Munich, Germany); Audiotapes.; Journalism--Germany.; Journalists.; Nationalism--Russia.; Radio broadcasting--Soviet Union.; Soviet Union--Emigration and immigration.; Veche (Munich, Germany)
- Group conversation in German, 1 sound tape reel (Box 114)
  Access
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009564
  Scope and Contents note
  Illegible(?) writing is on the accessioned tape box.
- Group conversation in German, 1 sound tape reel (Box 114)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009565
  This recording is a conversation in German between at least two people of both genders. It it interspersed with music in abrupt cuts as if the conversation was taped over a music tape.
- Short group conversation, 1 sound tape reel (Box 114)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009563
- Sound recording from 02 February 1976, 02 February 1976-02 March 0000; 1 sound tape reel (Box 114)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009560
  German male speaker(s).
- Sound recording from 06 July 1974, 1 sound tape reel (Box 114)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009557
  Oslo
- Sound recording from 21 February 1976, 1 sound tape reel (Box 114)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009568
- Sound recording from 29 June 1974, 1 sound tape reel (Box 114)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009555
- Sound recording from 30 January 1977, 1 sound tape reel (Box 114)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009570
- Sound recording from 8 July 1974, 08 July 1974; 1 sound tape reel (Box 114)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009552
  No. 2
- Sound recording from 8 July 1974, 08 July 1974; 1 sound tape reel (Box 114)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009556
  No. 3
- Unidentified female singer, 1 sound tape reel (Box 114)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009551
- Unidentified male folk singer recording, 1 sound tape reel (Box 114)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009567
  Illegible(?) writing on the accessioned tape box.
- Unidentified male folk singer recording, 1 sound tape reel (Box 114)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009583
  Writing on the tape box reads: Ta(?)y
- Unidentified male folk singer recording from 30 June 1974, 1 sound tape reel (Box 114)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009561
  The accessioned tape box has illegible(?) writing on it.
- Unidentified music recording, 1 sound tape reel (Box 114)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009584
  Studio recordings of a male singer and backing band. Sounds like it was sourced from an LP record.
- Unidentified, undated sound recording, 1 sound tape reel (Box 114)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009549
- Unidentified, undated sound recording, 1 sound tape reel (Box 114)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009577
- Unidentified, undated sound recording, 1 sound tape reel (Box 114)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009578
- Unidentified, undated sound recording, 1 sound tape reel (Box 114)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009579
  Illegible(?) handwriting on the accessioned tape box.
  Aurally, it sounds like a Radio Free Europe / Radio Liberty broadcast.
- Unidentified, undated sound recording, 1 sound tape reel (Box 114)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009581
  Aurally, this recording sounds like a Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty program.
- Unidentified, undated sound recording, 1 sound tape reel (Box 114)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009587
  Two male and one female voices are heard in the recording.
- Belarussian Program from 2 June 1976, 02 June 1976; 2 sound cassettes (Box 115)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009540
- Mikhelson, 1 sound compact cassette (Box 115)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009536
  This recording sounds like a musical play.
- Unidentified interview, 1 sound compact cassette (Box 115)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009537
  The cassette has significant labeling, though it is illegible to someone that only reads English. - JS, 3 July 2013
- Unidentified music recording, 1 sound tape reel (Box 115)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009548
- Unidentified music recordings, 1 sound compact cassette (Box 115)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009535
- Unidentified Radio Liberty program from 14 February 1976, 1 sound compact cassette (Box 115)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009538
- Yura Maximenko sings Moscow, 05 September 1976; 1 sound compact cassette (Box 115)
  Use copy reference number: 2013c19_a_0009539